<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>👩‍💻 Tobias Nilsson on Hi 👋 My name is Tobias.</title>
    <link>https://actuallava.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 👩‍💻 Tobias Nilsson on Hi 👋 My name is Tobias.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://actuallava.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Slackeee - Slack End-to-End Encryption</title>
      <link>https://actuallava.com/posts/slackeee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://actuallava.com/posts/slackeee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slackeee - Slack End-to-End Encryption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t really a blog post per se, but more of a &amp;ldquo;Hey, I did this thing&amp;rdquo;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a browser extension that adds end-to-end encryption to Slack messages. It started out as a small hackathon project, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been polishing it up and adding features since then.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The extension is available for Firefox, but written for cross-compatibility (I just haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten around to publishing it to the Chrome Web Store yet), and you can find the source code on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/halfspacer/slackeee&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Write Code Like George R.R. Martin</title>
      <link>https://actuallava.com/posts/writelikemartin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://actuallava.com/posts/writelikemartin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;George R.R. Martin, the writer behind A Song of Ice and Fire, is renowned for weaving intricate narratives with dozens of characters, sprawling kingdoms, and hidden plot threads—all while keeping readers engrossed. His secret? Clarity amidst complexity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Software architects and developers can learn a lot from Martin’s approach. Just as he ensures his epic tales remain accessible to readers, developers must write code that’s comprehensible to anyone who encounters it—especially those unfamiliar with its underlying complexities. This philosophy fosters modular design, extensibility, and maintainability while reducing bugs and accelerating junior developer onboarding. Let’s explore why coding like a storyteller pays dividends.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NativeAOT in .NET: Harder, Better, Faster, Stronger</title>
      <link>https://actuallava.com/posts/nativeaot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://actuallava.com/posts/nativeaot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;nativeaot-in-net-harder-better-faster-stronger&#34;&gt;NativeAOT in .NET: Harder, Better, Faster, Stronger&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over the past few months, I’ve been diving (sinking?) deep into the world of .NET performance optimizations as part of trying to write better cloud services with less hassle. &amp;ldquo;Switch to Go! Or Rust!&amp;rdquo; - I hear you.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;But now hear me out:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll share my personal experiences and practical tips on using NativeAOT to achieve rapid startup times and a smaller memory footprint in .NET applications—without any hype, just what worked for me, and all without having to leave the comforting embrace of Satya Nadella (CEO, Microsoft).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mobile VR’s Retro Renaissance</title>
      <link>https://actuallava.com/posts/mobilevroptimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://actuallava.com/posts/mobilevroptimization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mobile VR headsets like the Meta Quest 3 deliver astonishing immersion, but behind the sleek facade lies a harsh reality: these devices still battle the same fundamental constraints that plagued early 3D consoles. Thermal limits, power budgets, and stereo rendering demands have forced developers to rediscover an art we’d nearly forgotten—&lt;strong&gt;doing more with less&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-timeless-bottleneck&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Timeless Bottleneck&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every generation of hardware brings new capabilities, but three challenges remain eternal:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thermal Walls&lt;/strong&gt;: No one wants a headset that overheats mid-game&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pixel Overload&lt;/strong&gt;: Rendering two high-res views simultaneously&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Battery Anxiety&lt;/strong&gt;: Players won’t stay immersed if runtime is measured in minutes&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Modern rendering pipelines often exacerbate these issues. Photorealistic lighting models and physics-based materials, while beautiful, were born for desktop GPUs that guzzle power like sports cars. Mobile VR demands the efficiency of a hybrid engine—which is exactly where retro techniques shine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
